Guide to the Lyman Hoover Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Lyman Hoover Papers
1900-1977
RG 9
Yale University Divinity School Library
22
(56 boxes)
The collection relates to the personal and professional life of Lyman Hoover. There is valuable documentation of the work of the YMCA in China from 1930 until the Communist takeover in 1950, including observations of Chinese social and political conditions. Lyman Hoover was a missionary in China under the auspices of the YMCA (1930-1949) and a consultant and representative of the Asia Foundation (formerly known as Committee for a Free Asia) in New York and Taiwan.
Hoover, Lyman, 1901-
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lyman Hoover
Biographical / Historical
1901 Aug 5 Born in Minerva, Ohio, son of Virginia D. and Rev. Guy l. Hoover.
1922 Graduated from Butler University.
1922-1923 Traveling secretary for the Student Volunteer Movement.
1923-1928 Attended Yale Divinity School.
1924 Aug 5 Ordained at the Downey Avenue Christian Church, Indianapolis.
1924-1928 Served as pastor of the Congregational Church in Northford, Ct.
1925 Feb 7 Married Helen L. Kroenke.
1928-1930 Associate regional secretary of Rocky Mountain Field of National Student Division of YMCA's based in Denver.
1930 Aug Appointed to staff of International Committee of YMCA's for service in China.
1930-1932 Studied at the College of Chinese Studies, Peiping.
1931-1936 University Secretary of Peiping YMCA.
1932 Nov 19 Daughter, Carol Virginia, born.
1933-1936 Special lecturer at the College of Chinese Studies, Peiping in the field of Chinese Islam.
1936-1937 Furlough; one semester of study at Yale University. Returned to China without family.
1937 Jun 30 Son, Lyman MacNicholl, born (known as "Mac").
1938 Feb-Jul Five month, 5,000 mile tour of war-torn China. Assisted in organization of National Student Relief Committee.
1938 Appointed Associate Executives Student Division, National Committee, YMCA's of China.
1939 Apr Returned to China with family, based in Shanghai.
1939-1942 Associate Executive Secretary, National Student Relief Committee.
1939-1941 Member, Board of Managers, Shanghai American School.
1941 Jan Returned to U.S. with family LH returned to China 1941 Mar.
1941Jun YMCA headquarters in China transferred from Shanghai to Chungking,Szechuan because of war disturbances. LH worked from that base until 1945 Oct., his work including many long trips among the universities in exile in western China.
1942-1943 Administrative Secretary, National Student Relief Committee.
1943Apr Furlough in U.S.
1943 Elected Associate General Secretary, National Committee, YMCA's of China. LH had been offered the position of Executive Secretary of American Student YMCA but declined the position in order to continue his work in China.
1943 Dec-1944 Returned to China by sailing vessel, visiting YMCA work in South America, Africa, and India. While in China LH was a member of the Business and Educational Committees of United China Relief, the China Nutritional Aid Council and the Chinese American Institute of Cultural Relations.
1945Oct Returned from Chungking to Shanghai; helped reestablish National YMCA headquarters there. Supervised YMCA work for Japanese and Korean civilian internees and repatriates. Visited various cities and;univer sities in central and northern China, investigating rehabilitation problems. Member, Advisory Council, Chinese National Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.
1946 Jul-1948 Aug Furlough in U.S. First year spent largely in traveling and speaking engagements for YMCA.
1947-1948 School year spent in study for M.A. degree at Yale University, including major paper on issues of missionary preparation for overseas work.
1948 Aug-1947Jan Returned to Shanghai with family. Forced to return to U.S. because of health problems of HKH and unsettled conditions in China.
1949-1952 World Services Director for New York City YMCA.
1951 Appointed Trustee of United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia.
1951 Consultant to Committee for a Free Asia.
1952 Jun Appointed New York Representative of Committee for a Free Asia, which changed its name to the Asia Foundation in 1954.
1954, 1958 Visited Taiwan as Representative of Asia Foundation.
1964 Oct Helen K. Hoover died of heart failure.
1965 Mar "Mac" Hoover died of leukemia.
1965 Aug-1967 Nov Representative of Asia Foundation in Republic of China (Taiwan).
1968 Mar 16 Married Jane Hunter.
1969 Aug 9 Son, Giles, born.
1977 Jun Retired from Asia Foundation, having served as a consultant for his last ten years of association with the Foundation.
Scope and Contents
Lyman Hoover lived and worked in China for sixteen years during the period 1930-1949. His service in various administrative positions under the auspices of the International Committee of the Young Men's Christian Associations involved extensive travel throughout China and close cooperation with Chinese Christian leaders. The documentation of Hoover's work provided by this collection is of particular interest because of the nature of the YMCA's approach to mission work in China. To a greater extent than the missions enterprise of many denominational agencies, the activities of the YMCA in China were characterized by an awareness of and responsiveness to political events and by involvement of Chinese nationals in leadership roles.
While based in Peking, Shanghai or Chungking, Lyman Hoover spent long periods in travel throughout China and he and his YMCA colleagues became well-equipped to provide meaningful analysis of the religious, social, and political conditions that they observed The YMCA correspondence and reports in this collection include interesting comment on the progression of Communist influence in China, with awareness of Communist activities evident as early as 1931. In 1939, for example, Chinese YMCA staff member Kiang Wen Han reported on a trip to Yenan where he visited with university students living in caves and talked with Communist leaders Chou En Lai and Mao Tse Tung. Though Hoover was no longer in China at the height of the Communist takeover, he did continue to receive carbon copies of YMCA correspondence from China which related eyewitness accounts of the "liberation".
Various other topics are well documented by the Hoover Papers. Sino-Japanese relations and the extensive relief and rehabilitation operations carried on with YMCA cooperation during the World War II period are described in correspondence and reports. The study of the Islam religion in China was of particular interest to Hoover from the time that he wrote his B.D. thesis on that subject. The printed material gathered by Hoover during his years in China as well as correspondence with Islamic scholars such as Samuel Zwemer, Isaac Mason, and Claude L. Pickens, Jr. are a valuable resource for information regarding Chinese Muslims. A number of Chinese language pamphlets about Islam which Hoover collected have been placed in the East Asian Collection of the Yale University Library.
Also of interest are the materials in this collection which document Hoover's activities before and after his work in China. The completeness of the collection allows for careful analysis of the factors contributing to Hoover's decision to serve in China, a decision which he held to despite considerable odds. Hoover prepared for missionary service at the Yale Divinity School and the course notes he kept record the substance of lectures by Yale professors such as Kenneth Scott Latourette and Douglas Clyde Macintosh. After his return from China, Hoover completed nearly twenty-five years of work with the Asia Foundation (known as the Committee for a Free Asia prior to 1954). Serving as a consultant and liaison with Asian visitors and diplomats in New York, Hoover came in contact with notables such as U Thant, Dean Rusk, John D. Rockefeller, 3rd, and various Asian ambassadors.
The first series, CORRESPONDENCE, dates from 1902 to 1977 and is divided into Family Correspondence and General Correspondence. Hoover was separated from his family for long periods of time due to the traveling nature of his job, his wife's health and/or political disturbances in China. Letters exchanged between Hoover and his first wife clearly document the strains on family relationships which resulted from the demands of his work. Family correspondence, both within the immediate Hoover family and with the parents and siblings of Lyman and Helen is voluminous and provides a detailed picture of their daily routines and concerns. Early letters exchanged by Hoover's mother and father give insight into the environment in which he was brought up.
Of major importance in the General Correspondence section are the letters related to Hoover's work with the YMCA in China. All YMCA-related correspondence is gathered into one chronologically arranged file which includes letters exchanged with such YMCA notables as Eugene Barnett, Fletcher Brockman, Dalton McClelland, Lennig Sweet, Jay C. Oliver, Paul Moritz, S.C. Leung, Kiang Wen Han, Y.T. Wu and so forth. In conjunction with the printed material in Series II, these letters provide a valuable record of YMCA involvement in China during the period 1930-1950.
Also of interest in the General Correspondence section are Hoover's communications with Yale professors Kenneth S. Latourette and Clarence P. Shedd, his correspondence with the Islamic scholars mentioned above, and scattered contacts with China scholars and religious leaders such as John King Fairbank, Derk Bodde, Walter Judd, John R. Mott, Robert P. Wilder, and Henry P. VanDusen. Hoover exchanged courtesy correspondence with the various U.S. and Asian diplomats with whom he became acquainted through his work at the Asia Foundation. Throughout his career, Hoover corresponded with many Chinese religious leaders and acquaintances.
The second series, NOTES/SUBJECT FILE, consists of holograph notes as well as printed and typescript material dating from 1900 to 1976. These topically arranged materials relate to Hoover's student days, his professional involvements, speaking engagements, his study of Islam in China, a study of missionary preparation for overseas service, etc. One group of sermon :notes dating from 1900-1913 would appear to be those of Hoover's father, Guy Israel Hoover.
The third series, WRITINGS, is the smallest, consisting of twenty-two articles and essays written by Hoover The writings date from 1918 to 1948 and deal primarily with his personal beliefs and relationship to the missions movement, YMCA student work, and Muslims in China.
The fourth series, PERSONAL ITEMS AND MEMORABILIA, contains materials dating from 1907 to 1976 and is divided into six sections:
Biographical material
Diaries and appointment books
Financial material
Medical records
Memorabilia
Photographs
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1902-1970
II. Notes/subject File, 1900-1975
III. Writings, 1918-1948
IV. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1907-1976
Missionaries -- China; Missions -- China; Missions; Muslims -- China; Clergy; Missionaries; Fairbank, John King, 1907-1991; Hoover, Lyman, 1901-; Latourette, Kenneth Scott, 1884-1968; Mott, John R. (John Raleigh), 1865-1955; Wilder, Robert P., 1863-1938; Zwemer, Samuel Marinus, 1867-1952; Asia Foundation; Young Men's Christian Associations of China
- Correspondence, 1902-1970; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series is arranged as follows:
  1. Correspondence of the immediate family (1924-1967, n.d.)
  2 Correspondence of Helen Kroenke Hoover's family: mother, sisters andbrother-in-law (1928-1967, n.d.)
  3. Correspondence of Lyman Hoover's family: parents, siblings, in-laws(1928-1967, n.d.)
  B. General Correspondence-arranged alphabetically by author or recipient other than Hoover. Folders labeled with letters such as "A" or "Ba" are followed by individual folders for more notable or frequent correspondents. A large portion of the General Correspondence section is the YMCA-related correspondence file which is arranged chronologically. Personal correspondence with YMCA staff members is located under their names while business-related correspondence is located in the YMCA file.
  - Family Correspondence
    - Immediate family, 1924-1932 (Box 1, Folder 1-15)
    - Immediate family, 1933-1938 May (Box 2, Folder 16-32)
    - Immediate family, 1938 Jun-1944 Apr (Box 3, Folder 33-51)
    - Immedlate family, 1944 May-1954 (Box 4, Folder 52-69)
    - Immediate family, 1955-1967, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 70-77)
    - Family of HKH, 1928-1938 (Box 5, Folder 78-83)
    - Family of HKH, 1939-1967, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 84-87)
    - Family of LH, 1902-1940 (Box 6, Folder 88-99)
    - Family of LH, 1941-1967, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 100-116)
    - Family of LH: correspondence related to estate of Guy I. Hoover, 1943-1947 (Box 7, Folder 117)
  - General Correspondence
    - A - Al (Box 8, Folder 118)
    - Am - Ar (Box 8, Folder 119)
    - As - Ay (Box 8, Folder 120)
    - Ackley, Ernest, 1928-1951 (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals, Inc., 1952-1970 (Box 8, Folder 122)
    - American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, 1927-1949 (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - Ahlers, John, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - American Information Committee, 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - Archer, John Clark, 1923-1949 (Box 8, Folder 126)
    - Asia Foundation (see also: Committee for a Free Asia), 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 127)
    - Asia Foundation, 1958-1970 (Box 8, Folder 128-135)
    - Asia Magazine, 1935-1941 (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - Ba (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Be (Box 8, Folder 138)
    - Bi - B1 (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - Bo (Box 8, Folder 140)
    - Br (Box 8, Folder 141)
    - Bu (Box 8, Folder 142)
    - Bank of the Manhattan Company, 1944-1951 (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - Barnett, Bertha and Eugene (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1936-1967 (Box 8, Folder 144)
    - Bendtz, Arne (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1948-1957, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 145)
    - Bennett, E. S., 1937-1945 (Box 9, Folder 146)
    - Bishop, Merlin (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1966 (Box 9, Folder 147)
    - Bodde, Derk (see also: Notes/Subject File Missionary Preparation Study), 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 148)
    - Briggs, Ellsworth, 1922-1930 (Box 9, Folder 149)
    - British Government Agencies, 1942-1945 (Box 9, Folder 150)
    - Brunger, Harry (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1949-1962 (Box 9, Folder 151)
    - Butler University, 1919-1965 (Box 9, Folder 152-154)
    - Ca (Box 9, Folder 155)
    - Cha - Che (Box 9, Folder 156)
    - Chi - Chu (Box 9, Folder 157)
    - Cl - Col (Box 9, Folder 158)
    - Com - Cow (Box 9, Folder 159)
    - Cr - Cy (Box 9, Folder 160)
    - Canadian Government Agencies, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 161)
    - Canadian School of Missions, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 162)
    - Chang, Timothy, 1954-1964 (Box 9, Folder 163)
    - Chen, Francis, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 164)
    - China-Burma-India Veteran's Association, 1955-1965 (Box 9, Folder L65)
    - China Institute in America (see also: Friends of China in Westchester), 1946-1963 (Box 9, Folder 166)
    - China Nutritional Aid Council, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 167)
    - Chinese Government Agencies, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 168)
    - Chinese People's Army, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 168)
    - The Chinese Recorder, 1931-1940 (Box 9, Folder 169)
    - Chinese Students' Christian Association, 1939-1951, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 170-172)
    - Chrysler, Walter and Margaret, 1938-1940 (Box 9, Folder 173)
    - Chu, Rensen T., 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 174)
    - Chungking Missionary Association, 1944-1946 (Box 9, Folder 174A)
    - Church Missionary Society, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 174B)
    - Colvin, Harold and Reba (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1930-1966 (Box 9, Folder 174C)
    - Committee for a Free Asia (see also: Asia Foundation), 1951 Jan-Sep (Box 9, Folder 175)
    - Committee for a Free Asia, 1951 Oct-Dec (Box 9, Folder 176)
    - Committee for a Free Asia, 1952 -1953, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 177-179)
    - Committee on Friendly Relations Among Foreign Students, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - Community Church of Shanghai, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - Cooley, Frank, 1947, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - Cooper, Richard, 1948-1966 (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - Copland, Bruce and Margaret, 1931-1964, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 184)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, Inc., 1953-1965 (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - Cross, Rowland (see also: Foreign Missions Conference of North America), 1960 (Box 10, Folder 186)
    - Da - De (Box 10, Folder 187)
    - Di - Do (Box 10, Folder 188)
    - Dr - Du (Box 10, Folder 189)
    - DeJong, Garrett, 1922-1929 (Box 10, Folder 190)
    - Dodge, Cleveland E., 1952-1965 (Box 10, Folder 191)
    - Ec - Ei (Box 10, Folder 192)
    - El - Er (Box 10, Folder 193)
    - Edwards, Dwight and Mary (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1932-1965 (Box 10, Folder 194)
    - Engstrom, H. T., 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 195)
    - Eo-yang, Yu Ching, 1927-1933 (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - Evans, Roger, 1965-1977 (Box 10, Folder 197)
    - Fa (Box 10, Folder 198)
    - Fe - Fi (Box 10, Folder 199)
    - Fl - Fu (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - Fairbank, John K. (see also: Notes/Subject File - Missionary Preparation Study), 1955, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 201)
    - Fitch, George and Geraldine (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1943-1965 (Box 10, Folder 202)
    - Foreign Missions Conference of North America, 1946-1950 (Box 10, Folder 203)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1950-1951 (Box 10, Folder 204)
    - Friends' Ambulance Unit, Chungking, 1944-1945, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 205)
    - Friends of China in Westchester, 1952-1955, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 206-207)
    - Ga - Gi (Box 10, Folder 208)
    - Gl - Go (Box 11, Folder 209)
    - Gr (Box 11, Folder 210)
    - Garton, Maurice C., 1932-1939 (Box 11, Folder 211)
    - Glaser, Edna, 1931-1947. n.d (Box 11, Folder 212)
    - Greene, George H. and Agnes (see also:Committee for a Free Asia), 1936-1941 (Box 11, Folder 213)
    - Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1949-1958 (Box 11, Folder 214)
    - Ha - Har (Box 11, Folder 215)
    - Has - He (Box 11, Folder 216)
    - Hi - Ho (Box 11, Folder 217)
    - Us - Hw (Box 11, Folder 218)
    - Harris, George K., 1931, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 219)
    - Harrison, Paul, 1924-1931 (Box 11, Folder 220)
    - Hayes, John D. and Barbara, 1936-1954, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 221)
    - Edward W. Hazen Foundation, 1933-1949 (Box 11, Folder 222)
    - Hines, William (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1951-1975 (Box 11, Folder 223)
    - Howe, Howard A., 1925-1931, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 224)
    - Howell, Ernest (see also: Asia Foundation), 1956-1965, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 225)
    - Hu, C. S. Richard (see also: Society of Friends of Moslem in China), 1942-1945 (Box 11, Folder 226)
    - Hughel, Myron M., 1961-1967 (Box 11, Folder 227)
    - Hughes, E. R. and Katherine, 1931-1948 (Box 11, Folder 228)
    - I (Box 12, Folder 229)
    - Ikenberry, E. L. and Olivia, 1931-1932 (Box 12, Folder 230)
    - Immergluck, Edgar, 1947-1954 (Box 12, Folder 231)
    - International Missionary Council, 1931-1956 (Box 12, Folder 232)
    - International Red Cross, Chungking, 1944-1945 (Box 12, Folder 233)
    - Ja - Johnson, E. (Box 12, Folder 234)
    - Johnson, F. - Ju (Box 12, Folder 235)
    - Japan International Christian University, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 236)
    - Jeffrey, Arthur, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 237)
    - Johnston, Fannie Fern, 1913-1964 (Box 12, Folder 238)
    - Jones, Gordon N., 1930-1947 (Box 12, Folder 239)
    - Jorgensen, Charles and Dorothy (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1949 (Box 12, Folder 240)
    - Judd, Walter and Miriam (see also: Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals, Inc.), 1937-1952, n. d. (Box 12, Folder 241)
    - Ka - Ke (Box 12, Folder 242)
    - Kh - Kl (Box 12, Folder 243)
    - Kn - Kw (Box 12, Folder 244)
    - Kailan Mining Administration, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 245)
    - Kiang, Wen Han (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder 246)
    - Kracht, Eva, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 247)
    - La - Le (Box 12, Folder 248)
    - Li - Lin (Box 12, Folder 249)
    - Lit - Lo (Box 12, Folder 250)
    - Lu - Ly (Box 12, Folder 251)
    - Lacy, Carleton and Harriet, 1940-1950 (Box 12, Folder 252)
    - Latourette, Kenneth Scott, 1923-1966, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 253)
    - Leung, S. C. (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1952-1961 (Box 12, Folder 254)
    - Little, L. E. (see also: Committee for a Free Asia), 1954-1965 (Box 12, Folder 255)
    - Loh, Homer, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 256)
    - Ludwig, Gilbert and Isabelle, 1930-1936 (Box 12, Folder 257)
    - Ma - Mac (Box 12, Folder 258)
    - Mah - May (Box 12, Folder 259)
    - Me - Mi (Box 13, Folder 260)
    - Mo - Mu (Box 13, Folder 261)
    - McGavran, Donald, 1919-1954, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 262)
    - McKenny, Arthur, 1924-1931 (Box 13, Folder 263)
    - MacLeod, Virginia, 1929-1936, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 264)
    - Magill, Orrin and Ellen (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1946-1965 (Box 13, Folder 265)
    - Mason, Isaac, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 266)
    - Mehta, Nari and Nuvart, 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 267)
    - Miller, Herbert C. and Mary, 1925-1960, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 268)
    - Minard, Herbert (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1946-1966 (Box 13, Folder 269)
    - Moraes, Basil, 1943-1948 (Box 13, Folder 270)
    - Moritz, Paul and Margaret (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1939-1964, n.d (Box 13, Folder 271)
    - Morris, Carolyn (Mrs. G. W.), 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 272)
    - Mott, John R., 1931-1947 (Box 13, Folder 273)
    - Mu, Wen-Fu, 1933-1957, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 274)
    - Murray, J. Lovell, 1930-1948 (Box 13, Folder 275)
    - Na - Ne (Box 13, Folder 276)
    - No - Ny (Box 13, Folder 277)
    - National Christian Council of China, 1939-1945 (Box 13, Folder 278)
    - National City Bank of New York, 1939-1948 (Box 13, Folder 279)
    - National Library of Peiping Student Relief Committee (see: YMCA correspondence), 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 280)
    - Neustadt, Arthur, 1947-1949 (Box 13, Folder 281)
    - O (Box 13, Folder 282)
    - Oliver, Jay C. and Lucile (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1939-1966 (Box 13, Folder 283)
    - Olmstead, Robert G., 1949-1960 (Box 13, Folder 284)
    - Orbison, Telford, 1922-1966 (Box 13, Folder 285)
    - Osborn, George and Betty (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1932-1947 (Box 13, Folder 286)
    - Pa - Pas (Box 13, Folder 287)
    - Pat - Pax (Box 13, Folder 288)
    - Pe - Pf (Box 14, Folder 289)
    - Ph - Pi (Box 14, Folder 290)
    - PI - Py (Box 14, Folder 291)
    - Page, Kirby, 1922-1953 (Box 14, Folder 292)
    - Paton, David M. (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1942-1965, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 293)
    - Peking Union Church, 1934-1954 (Box 14, Folder 294)
    - Pickens, Claude L., Jr. and Elizabeth, 1928-1948 (Box 14, Folder 295)
    - Pickens, Claude L., Jr. and Elizabeth, 1951-1964 (Box 14, Folder 296)
    - Pope, Liston, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 297)
    - Presbyterian Church in the USA, Board of Foreign Missions, 1928--1929 (Box 14, Folder 298)
    - Price, Frank W., 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 299)
    - Q (Box 14, Folder 300)
    - Ra (Box 14, Folder 301)
    - Re (Box 14, Folder 302)
    - Ri - Ry (Box 14, Folder 303)
    - Remington, Alberta and Bertha, 1930-1939 (Box 14, Folder 304)
    - Report Letters of LH, 1931-1968 (Box 14, Folder 305)
    - Research and Training Institute for Physical and Health Education in China, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 306)
    - Rockefeller John D., 3rd, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 307)
    - Roy, Andrew and Margaret (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1932-1966 (Box 14, Folder 308)
    - Rugh, Dwight and Gertrude (see also: United China Relief), 1931-1966 (Box 14, Folder 309)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1960-1965 (Box 14, Folder 310)
    - Sa - Se (Box 14, Folder 311)
    - Sh (Box 14, Folder 312)
    - Si - S1 (Box 14, Folder 313)